<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Leo&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Leo&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 18:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://leotaba.blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Have you read...? Mangas from Inio Asano</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2025-02-22-inio-asano/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 18:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2025-02-22-inio-asano/</guid>
      <description>What a Wonderful World! What a Wonderful World! Brazilian edition cover My first contact with manga author Inio Asano was in the Sol Bookstore ⤴ in the ethnic Liberdade neighborhood ⤴ of São Paulo. I was just browsing random manga and the cover of What a Wonderful World!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Have you played...? Sea of Stars</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2025-02-01-sea-of-stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:14:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2025-02-01-sea-of-stars/</guid>
      <description>After getting this as a gift from a cousin on Christmas of 2023 (so more than a year ago 😬), I&amp;rsquo;ve finally decided to play it. There was a lot of buzz and hype for this game, so I was excited to try it. In a nutshell, Sea of Stars is a traditional turn-based JRPG with heavy inspiration from the SNES classics, especially Chrono Trigger (I&amp;rsquo;ll probably cite CT many more times throughout this post 😬). It&amp;rsquo;s a love letter to these timeless classics, with modern mechanics and sensibilities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Have you played...? The Final Fantasy Legend</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2025-01-12-the-final-fantasy-legend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 22:15:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2025-01-12-the-final-fantasy-legend/</guid>
      <description>After finishing U.N. Squadron, I wanted to play something I never played before. A short, old school JRPG seemed like a good choice for the next few days, so I chose &lt;strong&gt;The Final Fantasy Legend&lt;/strong&gt;, released in 1989 for the Game Boy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Have you played...? U.N. Squadron</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2025-01-11-un-squadron/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:35:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2025-01-11-un-squadron/</guid>
      <description>I wanted this to be part of the Mini Reviews 1 post to have an SNES game there, but I wasn’t able to finish it in time it’s a hard one. Like the other games in that post, I first played U.N. Squadron when I was a kid, around 8 or so I think. Back then I actually played the original Japanese version, which is called Area 88 (エリア88), which was based on a manga and anime of the same name.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mini Reviews 1: Elemental Master, Castle of Illusion Starring Mickey Mouse, Tiny Toon Adventures 2: Trouble in Wackyland</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2025-01-01-mini-reviews-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 22:05:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2025-01-01-mini-reviews-1/</guid>
      <description>During the holiday break I used my Anbernic RG40XXV to play and finish 3 games I had played during my childhood, each one for a different console. It was a little weird playing them on a crisp LED screen, without the CRT TV blurring - they almost felt like different games than the ones I remembered 😂.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Have you played...? Lufia &amp; The Fortress of Doom</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-12-28-lufia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 13:30:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-12-28-lufia/</guid>
      <description>Lufia &amp;amp; The Fortress of Doom is an old school SNES JRPG. It&amp;rsquo;s grindy, repetitive, and annoying sometimes, but it&amp;rsquo;s charming in its simplicity. It&amp;rsquo;s a 16 bit RPG with an 8 bit soul.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review: Anbernic RG40XXV</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-12-23-review-anbernic-rg40xxv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 01:28:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-12-23-review-anbernic-rg40xxv/</guid>
      <description>There are many old games, particularly RPGs, from the 16-bit era that I want to play, or that I started playing when I was a kid and never saw the ending: Lufia 1 &amp;amp; 2, Final Fantasy 6, Phantasy Star II, Shining Force, to cite only a few.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fighting games and piano</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-11-27-fighting-games-and-piano/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:01:59 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-11-27-fighting-games-and-piano/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago I was spacing out and started thinking how doing combos in fighting games is a little like playing a music on piano. You have to get the inputs/notes right, at the right time, at the right rhythm, otherwise it doesn&amp;rsquo;t connect, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound right.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Have you played...? Monotype</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-11-25-monotype/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 23:59:39 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-11-25-monotype/</guid>
      <description>Monotype is a short philosophical/horror visual novel about a virtual pet that&amp;rsquo;s made real. I don&amp;rsquo;t even remember when I put it in my Steam library, but I decided to play it as I&amp;rsquo;m trying to play more instead of buying more games.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alerta: Phishing com azeite de oliva</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-07-21-phishing-com-azeite-de-oliva/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 19:03:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-07-21-phishing-com-azeite-de-oliva/</guid>
      <description>(post in Portuguese since this is a scam alert aimed at Brazilians) Sou um usuário ávido do Youtube e geralmente nem percebo as propagandas que aparecem no meio da lista de outros vídeos. Porém, nessa semana uma delas me chamou a atenção: 5 azeites de oliva Andorinha por R$89,90?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Have you played...? Minoria</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-07-12-minoria/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 01:31:07 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-07-12-minoria/</guid>
      <description>By now you know I love indie games, but I have even more consideration when they&amp;rsquo;re made by my fellow Brazilian compatriots. Brazil isn&amp;rsquo;t known as a big game making country, but we do have some gems here. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t call Minoria a gem, but it&amp;rsquo;s a nice game overall.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Have you played...? Refind Self: The Personality Test Game</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-06-09-refind-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 19:07:20 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-06-09-refind-self/</guid>
      <description>This is definitely an odd one. I was intrigued by the game&amp;rsquo;s propsal as a personality test, and the pretty screenshots in the Steam page convinced me to try it. I love weird games so I knew I&amp;rsquo;d like this one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Have you played...? Grimm&#39;s Hollow</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-06-08-grimms-hollow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 18:40:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-06-08-grimms-hollow/</guid>
      <description>I think I&amp;rsquo;ve already said that, but I love short games with a nice narrative. Grimm&amp;rsquo;s Hollow is a small RPG Maker game that tells a simple and touching story about grief and loss. We follow Lavender, a young girl, as she wakes up in a strange place called Grimm&amp;rsquo;s Hollow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Motocross Maniacs OST</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-04-02-motocross-maniacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 22:25:20 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-04-02-motocross-maniacs/</guid>
      <description>So, the other day I was listening to the Rhythm and Pixels Radio ⤴ while working. Some days I feel that 8-bit old game music really goes well with programming, it helps me get into the groove. One of the songs that played caught my attention though:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Have you played...? BAD END THEATER</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-02-09-bad-end-theater/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 23:44:37 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-02-09-bad-end-theater/</guid>
      <description>I bought this some months ago captivated by its premise: a weird game where you decide characters&amp;rsquo; fates as if in a theater play, with cute, 8-bit aesthetic? Sign me in! Steam reviews were also overwhelmingly positive and it was not expensive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Have you played...? Ann</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-01-14-ann/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 16:19:30 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2024-01-14-ann/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m at the point in my Steam games library where I can&amp;rsquo;t remember why I have some games - that&amp;rsquo;s the case for this one. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just a a sucker for meganekko. Actually, I think it was because I came across this funny Youtube video and decided to see what else the creator had done.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(Piano cover) OMORI - Duet</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2023-05-04-piano-cover-omori-duet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 01:43:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2023-05-04-piano-cover-omori-duet/</guid>
      <description>Composed by Pedro Silva Arrangement by Pianobin ⤴ One of the most beautiful and touching moments in videogame history.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(Piano cover) OMORI - By Your Side</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2023-04-30-piano-cover-omori-by-your-side/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 01:43:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2023-04-30-piano-cover-omori-by-your-side/</guid>
      <description>Composed by Pedro Silva Arrangement by salmonghoul on MuseScore &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ll forgive yourself&amp;hellip; Won&amp;rsquo;t you&amp;hellip; SUNNY?&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Have you played...? OMORI</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2022-05-09-omori/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 20:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2022-05-09-omori/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finished OMORI recently and enjoyed it a lot. The story and narrative are well developed, and some moments were truly moving. Be wary that it&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful but also particularly dark and heavy story about the struggle against depression and traumas that can be very real.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Have you played...? Dweller&#39;s Empty Path</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2021-08-21-dwellers-empty-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 20:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2021-08-21-dwellers-empty-path/</guid>
      <description>Dweller&amp;rsquo;s Empty Path is a very short (2-3 hours long) and lighthearted game, but has its contemplative and touching moments too. It is a retro-styled, character-driven, exploration-based RPG Maker game, as we follow protagonist Yoki on a day of her life, trying to clear her mind and get a good night of sleep after waking up from a strange nightmare.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Você já jogou...? VA-11 Hall-A: Cyberpunk Bartender Action</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2018-03-29-va-11-hall-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2018-03-29-va-11-hall-a/</guid>
      <description>Em um futuro próximo, existe uma cidade distópica onde grandes corporações dominam o governo, e a população, oprimida, luta para sobreviver a cada dia. Nessa cidade há um pequeno bar chamado VA-11 Hall-A, apelidado Valhalla, que é visitado por pessoas que buscam uma bebida, um pouco de alento e, talvez, uma conversa amiga.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Você já leu...? Repeteco</title>
      <link>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2017-02-16-repeteco/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://leotaba.blog/posts/2017-02-16-repeteco/</guid>
      <description>Quadrinhos são muito mais que super heróis de colante ou garotos de cabelos espetados salvando o mundo. Que tal uma chef de cozinha descontente com sua vida e que quer abrir seu próprio restaurante? Essa é a premissa inicial de Repeteco, a mais recente graphic novel de Bryan Lee O&amp;rsquo;Malley, famoso pela série Scott Pilgrim.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
